# Jordi Català

### contact

+34 611 14 41 70

jordicatalaamat@gmail.com

Remote London, UK Barcelona, ES

### languages

English - proficient Catalan - native Spanish - native French - beginner

### soft skills

Empathy, Quick Adaptability, Effective Communication, Open-Minded, Independence, Collaborative Spirit, Problem-Solving, Leadership, Reliability, Time Management

### programming

♥ React, ♥ React-Native,♥ Node, ♥ Typescript, ♥ C#

### miscellaneous

CSS3, ES6, SOA, ESB, CQRS, Eventsourcing, Flux/Redux, Styled Components, Material UI, NextJS, Tamagui, SOLID, TDD, DDD, RabbitMQ, IIS, TeamCity, Docker, CircleCI, Octopus Deploy, SVN/GIT/TFS, Jira, MongoDB, RavenDB, Kubernetes, PostgreSQL, SQL Server, Oracle PL/SQL

### interests

Personal Development, Yoga & Mindfulness, Long Distance Hiking, Rock Climbing, Self-Built Camper Van, Photography

### holistic

Wondering about my **career transitions**? In-depth overview on the **third page** 

## synopsis

I am an enthusiastic software engineer with a degree in Computer Software and over ten years of hands-on experience in both product and service-based business, across full stack development and employing agile methodologies. More than a developer. I take pride in the work I undertake and firmly believe in owning the products I work on.

I have worked in designing products; developing mobile apps and web-based software; crafting REST and GraphQL APIs; producing SOLID, well-tested implementations following TDD; and using Continuous Integration to deploy to cloud-based infrastructure.

I engage deeply with the product, constantly aiming to deliver the best experience to users. I am known for my adaptability in high-paced environments and my aptitude for quickly grasping new concepts and challenges.

# **experience**

2020/07-2023/07 IT Freelancer & Spiritual Counsellor

Remote, London, Spain

Spiritual Counsellor, Digital Strategist, Coach Career transition to coach, guide, and digital strategist.

- Part-Time Full Stack Freelancer.
- Digital Advisor for Holistic Health & Coaching Businesses: employed my technical prowess to help holistic health practitioners amplify their digital visibility, refining their social media strategies, enhancing their websites and creating resonating online content using Al tools.
- Theta Healing Instructor: certified instructor through this meditation technique to stimulate deep emotional, spiritual, and physical healing.

**Tech Stack:** Leadership, Coaching, People Skills, Meditation, Wordpress, Ecommerce, React, TypeScript, Node, AWS

### 2020/02-2020/07 **Tinto (tintoapp.com)**

London, United Kingdom

Head of Engineering & CTO (React Native, Node & AWS) - Contractor (Remote) Empowering women in motherhood to thrive with tailored support.

- Overseeing engineering team, mentoring junior AI engineers, and ensuring smooth user experience.
- Playing a pivotal role in planning, product management, and migration of infrastructure to in-house servers.

**Tech Stack:** React-Native, TypeScript, Redux, Detox, Jest, Node, Docker, Agile, AWS

### 2019/04-2019/08 **Just Insurance (just.insure)**

London, United Kingdom

Full Stack Engineer (React Native, Node & AWS) - Contractor Driving insurance innovation with data-driven, pay-per-mile coverage.

- React Native & API development for iOS and Android.
- Admin tasks and release management for iOS and Android, utilising fastlane build automation, CERTS, Provisioning Profiles, and CircleCI.
- Developent of tracking systems.
- Migration of React Native codebase and integration with services Crashlytics, CircleCI, Apple Connect, Sentry, Git, AuthO, and Slack.

**Tech Stack:** React-Native, Jest, TypeScript, Navigation, Styled Components, Redux, Husky, Enzyme, Cypress, NodeJS, Firebase, PostgreSQL, Heroku, CircleCI, Agile

# Jordi Català

#### 2016/04-2018/11 **Movebubble (movebubble.com)**

London, United Kingdom

Full Time Full Stack Engineer (React Native, React, Node, C#) - Hybrid Movebubble simplifies the process of renting a new home. My role involved on both, the Renter (React) and the Negotiator (React-Native) Apps.

- Transitioning to full stack engineering in React & React-Native.
- Leading the development of the Negotiator App (React Native) from prototype to main value product, and taking ownership of the ReactJS app by implementing the Movebubble One concept.
- Achieving seamless API deployment from Dev to Production within minutes and consistently delivering new app versions every two weeks.
- · Mentoring of junior full stack developers.
- GV Design Sprints, Sprint Planning, Design of Experiment, Analytics, A/B & User Testing, ensuring high-quality code & user experience.
- Introducing and demonstrating the value of remote working to the CEO.

**Tech Stack:** React-Native, ReactJS, Node, Typescript, GraphQL, Cypress, Jest, C# ASP.NET, TDD, RavenDB, MongoDB, SQL, Octopus Deploy, Scrum, GV Design Sprint

### 2014/12-2016/04 PWC PricewaterhouseCoopers

London, United Kingdom

Full Time Backend Engineer (C#)

As a Backend Engineer on the TAX development team, my primary focus was on API development and scheduler file processing. My role involved creating robust and efficient APIs to deliver comprehensive tax solutions.

• Optimising the scheduler file processing system by implementing an ESB/SOA architecture, leveraging EventSourcing and RabbitMQ, improving overall performance and efficiency.

**Tech Stack:** C# ASP.NET Web API, TDD, JavaScript, PL/SQL, SQL Server, EF, MongoDB, EventSourcing (ESB), TeamCity, Octopus Deploy, Agile/Scrum

#### 2013/01-2014/11 MRW (mrw.es)

Barcelona, Spain

Full Time Backend Engineer (C#)

MRW is a well-known courier and logistics company based in Barcelona, Spain. They specialize in providing delivery services for both businesses and individuals, offering efficient and reliable solutions for their customers' needs. My role involved building a package delivery management system web-app.

- Implemented a robust SOA architecture, utilizing EventSourcing and CQRS with over 40 autonomous components (ACs).
- Mentored closely by the lead backend architecture developer.
- · Gained extensive experience in debugging EventSourcing.
- Responsible for integrating the V2 app with the V3 web-app, ensuring a seamless transition and user experience.

**Tech Stack:** C# ASP.NET MVC, DDD, TDD, JavaScript, jQuery, Knockout, MongoDB, SQL Server, EventSourcing (ESB, SOA, CQRS), RabbitMQ, TeamCity, Agile/Scrum

## education

2009-2013

**Diploma in Computer Software** 

Polytechnic University of Catalonia - FIB, Barcelona, Spain

# Jordi Català

### certified holistic

### **Healing & Holistic Therapy**

Theta Healing Advanced Practitioner & Instructor Access Consciousness Plant Medicine Facilitator Reiki Master Space Holder

### **Yoga & Embodiment**

200h Kundalini Yoga 60h Mind & Meditation Yoga 200h Ashtanga Vinyasa Yoga 100h Yin Yoga Laughter & Children Yoga

### holistic

Over the course of three years, from 2017 to 2020, I consciously took some time off to invest in personal development while travelling. Spain, France, the UK, Germany, India, Nepal, Portugal, Estonia, the USA, Kenya, and Thailand, my experiences were diverse, ranging from serious commitments to health and well-being, educational courses, to thrilling adventures.

While I remain dedicated and passionate about my work, I also hold a strong belief in the importance of sustaining a healthy mind and body. This conviction comes from understanding that our overall well-being significantly impacts our professional life and personal experiences. As I navigate my professional commitments, I make a conscious effort to uphold this balance, striving for an equilibrium in work and life.

In the post-2020 era, following the onset of the pandemic, my personal journey took an inward turn, encouraging me to deepen my self-realisation journey further. I actively sought and embraced ways to cultivate personal growth and to promote holistic well-being in others and shaped my next career step - transitioning into a space holder / coaching role. It equipped me with a robust set of tools to assist others on their personal and spiritual journeys, to uncover and realise their highest potential.

In this deeply transformative period of my life, I was not only embarking on a new professional path, but I was also entering a new personal phase. Amidst these profound experiences and learnings, I got married to my wife. She was a fellow traveller on this spiritual and holistic journey. Together, we extended our support to holistic practitioners and fellow community members to enhance their digital presence and increase their online reach.

Today, I feel a strong pull towards returning to the technology sector. Throughout my journey, I've continuously been merging my skills and interests, interweaving technology with spiritual practice and interpersonal growth. As a result, I believe I have a unique set of gifts that I am now ready to offer in this space again.

2020/07-2023/06 IT Freelancer, Deep Personal Transformation Coach

USA, Spain, France, Mexico

Digital Advisor, Spiritual Counsellor, Coach, Plant Medicine Facilitator

- Plant Medicine Facilitator: providing safe, sacred, and effective healing spaces where individuals can explore their consciousness and engage with plant medicines for spiritual growth and emotional healing.
- Access Consciousness Practitioner & Coach: a pragmatic methodology that fosters increased conscious awareness.

2017/08-2020/01 **Travelling** 

Spain, France, UK, Germany, India, Nepal, etc

Personal Development

- India & Thailand: More than 500h Yoga TTC in Kundalini with *Golden Bridge Yoga*, Ashtanga Vinyasa & Yin with *The Yoga People*.
- · Madrid, Spain: Children Yoga TTC with Rainbow Yoga.
- Cirque de Gavarnie and Ordesa y Monte Perdido National Park, France & Spain: Completed a summit of 15 peaks over 3000m (9800ft) in 5 days.
- Corsica, France: 180km GR20, the toughest long distance trail in Europe.